Guide to the Albert Waldo Snoke Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- General Files, 1917-1988; Series I
  - Gehrig, Leo J., 1979 (Box 8, Folder 152)
  - Geibel, Edgar, 1959-1988 (Box 8, Folder 153)
  - Geiser, Marion and Peter, 1984-1987 (Box 8, Folder 154)
  - Giamo, Robert, 1966-1969 (Box 8, Folder 155)
  - Ginsberg, Eli, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 156)
  - Gonzalez, Jose, 1962-1985 (Box 8, Folder 157)
  - Grace-New Haven Community Hospital, 1946-1966 (Box 8, Folder 158)
    See also: folder 416
  - Grace-New Haven Community Hospital Women's Auxiliary, 1949-1967 (Box 9, Folder 159)
  - Grant, Laura, 1950-1955 (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - Grave, Richard M., 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 161)
  - Grove, William, 1968-1972 (Box 9, Folder 162)
  - Ha (Box 9, Folder 163)
  - He-Hi (Box 9, Folder 164)
  - Ho-Hy (Box 9, Folder 165)
  - Hague, James E., 1955-1988 (Box 9, Folder 166-167)
    - Audiotapes
      - Response to Albert Snokes letter of 1985 Oct 4, 1 audiotape (cassette), 90 mins. (Box 56)
        Conditions Governing Access
        Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
      - Response to Albert Snokes letter of 1987 Feb 13, 1 audiotape (cassette) (Box 57)
      - Comments on chapter draft Hospitals, Health, and People, Undated; 1 audiotape (cassette) (Box 58)
  - Halamandris, Val, 1982-1987 (Box 9, Folder 168)
  - Hall, Diana Long
    See: folder 226
  - Hamilton, Esther and Marsha, 1984-1988 (Box 9, Folder 169)
  - Hamilton, Fay
    See: folder 197
  - Hamilton, T. Stewart, 1956-1988 (Box 9, Folder 170)
  - Hamilton, Walter Raleigh and Mattie, 1939-1953 (Box 9, Folder 171)
  - Hanawalt family, 1937-1986 (Box 9, Folder 172)
  - Hawaii (state), 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 173)
  - Heerman, Ritz E., 1955-1956 (Box 10, Folder 174)
  - Heintz, Stephen, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 175)
  - Heppner, Myer, 1965-1984 (Box 10, Folder 176)
  - Hess, Arthur E., 1975-1985 (Box 10, Folder 177)
    See also: folder 81
  - Heyssel, Robert M., 1980-1983 (Box 10, Folder 178)
  - Hill, Vernon, 1974-1985 (Box 10, Folder 179)
  - Holderman, James B., 1972 (Box 10, Folder 180)
  - Hospice, Inc., 1972-1980 (Box 10, Folder 181)
  - Hospital Administration Correspondence Club, 1962-1975 (Box 10, Folder 182)
  - Hospital of St. Raphael, 1986-1988 (Box 10, Folder 183)
  - Hospital Society of New York, 1973-1983 (Box 10, Folder 184)
  - Hospitals, 1951-1956 (Box 10, Folder 185)
    See also: folders 10-15, 296
  - I (Box 10, Folder 186)
  - Illinois (state), 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 187)
    See also: folders 35, 39, 114, 122, 134, 138, 180, 223-225, 253, 289-293, 431, 435
  - Illinois Hospital Association, 1967-1972 (Box 10, Folder 188)
  - Ingelfinger, Franz J.
    See: folder 280
  - Ives, A. G. L. and Doris, 1958-1977 (Box 10, Folder 189)
  - Ives, John and Ann, 1964-1985 (Box 10, Folder 190)
  - J (Box 10, Folder 191)
  - Jersey City Medical Center, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 192)
    See also: folders 237-238, 297
  - Jewish Home for the Aged, New Haven, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 193)
  - Johns, Edwin, 1948-1953 (Box 10, Folder 194)
  - Johnson, Emery, 1976-1984 (Box 10, Folder 195)
  - Joint Commission on Accreditation of Hospitals, 1963-1976 (Box 11, Folder 196)
  - Jones, John Paul and Fay Hamilton, 1937-1971 (Box 11, Folder 197)
  - Jones, Wanda J., 1970-1980 (Box 11, Folder 198)
  - Jose, Bryce and Ruth, 1981-1985 (Box 11, Folder 199)
  - Ka-Kh (Box 11, Folder 200)
  - Ki-Ko (Box 11, Folder 201)
  - Kr-Ku (Box 11, Folder 202)
  - Keiser, A. Kay, 1972-1978 (Box 11, Folder 203)
  - Kentucky Council on Public Higher Education, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 204)
  - Keppel, Katherine A., 1973-1986 (Box 11, Folder 205)
  - Kidson, Warren and Lynn, 1973-1984 (Box 11, Folder 206)
  - King, Sheldon, 1983-1988 (Box 11, Folder 207)
  - Kinzer, David, 1971-1988 (Box 11, Folder 208)
  - Kissick, William L., 1973-1985 (Box 11, Folder 209)
  - Kligerman, Morton M., 1958-1961 (Box 11, Folder 210)
  - Knapp, Richard, 1976-1985 (Box 11, Folder 211)
  - Knowles, John, 1969-1979 (Box 12, Folder 212)
  - Kramer, Paul R., 1977-1987 (Box 12, Folder 213)
  - Kroger, Hilda, 1953-1982 (Box 12, Folder 214)
  - La-Le (Box 12, Folder 215)
  - Li-Ly (Box 12, Folder 216)
  - Lamont, Austin, 1953-1954 (Box 12, Folder 217)
  - Law, John T. and Mary Ellen, 1954-1986 (Box 12, Folder 218)
  - Lawrence and Memorial Associated Hospitals, 1954-1967 (Box 12, Folder 219)
  - Lee, Sidney, 1980-1982 (Box 12, Folder 220)
  - Leutwiler, Lester G., 1983-1986 (Box 12, Folder 221)
  - Levin, Peter J., 1977-1982 (Box 12, Folder 222)
  - Levy, Jay
    See: folder 229
  - Lindsley, George, 1971-1987 (Box 12, Folder 223-225)
  - Long, Diana, 1983-1986 (Box 13, Folder 226)
  - Long, Hilda, 1967-1985 (Box 13, Folder 227)
  - Ludlam, James, 1955-1968 (Box 13, Folder 228)
  - Lustman, Stanley, 1978-1982 (Box 13, Folder 229)
  - Lyman, Richard, 1977-1979 (Box 13, Folder 230)
  - Ma (Box 13, Folder 231)
  - Me-Mi (Box 13, Folder 232)
  - Mo-My (Box 13, Folder 233)
  - MacLean, Basil C., 1937-1986 (Box 13, Folder 234)
  - MacLean, Carrie, 1979-1987 (Box 13, Folder 235)
  - Malloy, James
    - 1968-1976 (Box 13, Folder 236)
    - 1977-1988 (Box 14, Folder 237-238)
  - Mann, Kalman J., 1951-1981 (Box 14, Folder 239)
  - Mannix, John R., 1984-1987 (Box 14, Folder 240)
  - Manz family, 1960-1987 (Box 14, Folder 241)
  - Marina Cay [resort], 1979-1986 (Box 14, Folder 242)
  - Marmor, Theodore R., 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 243)
  - Marsh, Robert J.
    See: folder 64
  - Martin, Mabel G., 1961-1962 (Box 14, Folder 244)
  - Maslan, Neal S., 1965-1987 (Box 14, Folder 245)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, 1952-1984 (Box 14, Folder 246)
  - Massachusetts Health Organization, 1971-1974 (Box 14, Folder 247)
  - Massey, Robert U., 1977-1988 (Box 14, Folder 248)
  - Masur, Henry, 1980-1987 (Box 14, Folder 249)
  - Masur, Jack, 1947-1969 (Box 14, Folder 250)
  - Mawby, Russell G., 1979 (Box 14, Folder 251)
  - May, Dennis P., 1981-1988 (Box 14, Folder 252)
  - McCarter, John, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 253)
  - McCarthy, Carol, 1985-1988 (Box 14, Folder 254)
  - McCollum, Robert, 1977-1986 (Box 15, Folder 255)
  - McLamb, J. D. and Frances, 1976-1980 (Box 15, Folder 256)
  - McMahon, John Alexander, 1972-1988 (Box 15, Folder 257-258)
  - McNerney, Walter, 1965-1987 (Box 15, Folder 259)
  - McNulty, Matthew F., 1969-1980 (Box 15, Folder 260)
  - Medical Administrators Conference, 1968-1987 (Box 15, Folder 261)
  - Medical Superintendents' Club, 1948-1950 (Box 15, Folder 262)
  - Meld, Murray
  - Milbank Memorial Fund, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 263)
  - Milbrook Association, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 264)
  - Miller, Caroline Snoke
    See: folder 357
  - Miller, Richard and Faith, 1983-1988 (Box 15, Folder 265)
  - Miller, Robert, 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 266)
  - Modern Hospital
    See: folder 108
  - Montgomery, Tom and Madeleine, 1958-1980 (Box 15, Folder 267)
  - Mood, Eric, 1972-1987 (Box 15, Folder 268)
  - Morris, Stephen, 1972-1984 (Box 15, Folder 269)
  - Morrissey, Edward F.
    - 1967-1977 (Box 15, Folder 270)
    - 1978-1986, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 271-273)
  - Mosher, Carl L.
    See: folders 309-316
  - Motameni, Saeed T., 1961-1978 (Box 16, Folder 274)
  - Mulvihill, James, 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 275)
  - N (Box 16, Folder 276)
  - Nagle, Paul, 1974-1977 (Box 16, Folder 277)
  - Nassif, Raif E., 1972-1987 (Box 16, Folder 278)
  - Nelson, Russell A., 1953-1983 (Box 16, Folder 279)
  - New England Journal of Medicine, 1974-1982 (Box 16, Folder 280)
  - New Haven Foundation, 1976-1982 (Box 16, Folder 281)
  - New Haven Health Care, Inc., 1972-1975 (Box 16, Folder 282)
  - New York Academy of Medicine, 1969-1974 (Box 16, Folder 283)
  - New York State Health Preparedness Committee, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 284)
  - New Zealand, 1972-1975 (Box 17, Folder 285)
  - Newton, Dale, 1977-1979 (Box 17, Folder 286)
  - Newton, Quigg
    See: folder 82
  - Nicklas, John, 1968-1975 (Box 17, Folder 287)
  - O (Box 17, Folder 288)
  - Ogilvie, Richard, 1968-1986 (Box 17, Folder 289-293)
  - Ogrean, Richard, 1966-1979 (Box 18, Folder 294)
  - Olmsted, William and Jane, 1954-1983 (Box 18, Folder 295)
  - Olsen, Rex, 1972-1988 (Box 18, Folder 296)
  - O'Neil, Bernard J., 1975-1985 (Box 18, Folder 297)
  - Oregon, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 298)
  - Owen, Jack, 1975-1984 (Box 18, Folder 299)
  - Pa (Box 18, Folder 300)
  - Pe-Py (Box 18, Folder 301)
  - Pellegrino, Edmund D., 1975-1978 (Box 18, Folder 302)
  - Pennsylvania (state), 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 303)
  - Peter, Laurence J. and Irene, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 304)
  - Petersen, John R., 1965-1983 (Box 18, Folder 305)
  - Piper, Kenneth M., 1972-1973 (Box 18, Folder 306)
  - Plumb, Elizabeth
    See: folder 76
  - Pope, Liston, 1977-1987 (Box 18, Folder 307)
  - Porterfield, John
  - Prekup, Joseph T., 1967-1982 (Box 18, Folder 308)
  - Presbyterian Hospital in Philadelphia, 1962-1965 (Box 19, Folder 309-314)
    See also: folders 336, 347, 315-316
  - Presbyterian-University of Pennsylvania Medical Center, 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 315-316)
  - Price, Lori, 1985-1986 (Box 19, Folder 317)
  - Q (Box 19, Folder 318)
  - Ra-Re (Box 19, Folder 319)
  - Rh-Ror (Box 20, Folder 320)
  - Ros-Ry (Box 20, Folder 321)
  - Redlich, Frederick G., 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 322)
  - Regional Visiting Nurse Agency, Inc.
    - General, 1977-1988 (Box 20, Folder 323)
    - Phelps Community Project Committee, 1982-1988 (Box 20, Folder 324)
  - Reilly family, 1974-1986 (Box 20, Folder 325)
  - Ribicoff, Abraham, 1965-1974 (Box 20, Folder 326)
  - Riggan family, 1975-1987 (Box 20, Folder 327)
  - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, 1972-1986 (Box 20, Folder 328)
  - Roberts, Elliot
  - Robinson, Barclay, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 329)
  - Robson, George Bernard, 1962-1988 (Box 20, Folder 330)
  - Roensch, Burns, 1978-1988 (Box 20, Folder 331)
  - Roger, David E.
    See: folder 328
  - Root, Wallace, 1978-1988 (Box 20, Folder 332)
  - Rorem, C. Rufus, 1951-1969 (Box 20, Folder 333)
  - Rosenfeld, E. D., 1965-1979 (Box 20, Folder 334)
  - Roth, Russell, 1969-1974 (Box 20, Folder 335)
  - Rourke, Anthony J. J. and Dorothy, 1953-1983 (Box 21, Folder 336)
  - Rytand, David, 1956-1988 (Box 21, Folder 337-339)
  - Sa-Se (Box 21, Folder 340)
  - Sh-Sl (Box 21, Folder 341)
  - Sm-So (Box 21, Folder 342)
  - Sp-Sw (Box 21, Folder 343)
  - Samaritan Health Service, 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 344)
    See also: folders 269, 306, 308
  - Sams, Bruce Jones
    See: folder 363
  - Scheffer, Victor, 1979-1987 (Box 21, Folder 345)
  - Schmidt, Alexander, 1985-1986 (Box 22, Folder 346)
  - Sebring, Orvel, 1954-1965 (Box 22, Folder 347)
  - Sheps, Cecil G., 1981-1987 (Box 22, Folder 348)
  - Sigmond, Robert M., 1957-1982 (Box 22, Folder 349)
  - Smith, C. Thomas, 1978-1985 (Box 22, Folder 350)
  - Smith, Carlton H., 1963-1984 (Box 22, Folder 351)
  - Smith, Claudia
    See: folder 324
  - Snoke, Albert Thomas and Mary Teresa Flynn and family, 1944-1988 (Box 22, Folder 352)
  - Snoke, Barbara, 1979-1988 (Box 22, Folder 353)
  - Snoke, Frank M., 1969-1982 (Box 22, Folder 354)
  - Snoke, John Arthur and Judith Houtz and family, 1944-1988 (Box 22, Folder 355)
  - Snoke, John Waldo and Helen, 1917-1942 (Box 22, Folder 356)
  - Snoke, Michael D. and Caroline and family, 1957-1988 (Box 22, Folder 357)
  - Snoke, Parnie Storey, 1932-1978, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 358-361)
  - Snoke family, 1962-1966, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 362)
  - Society of Medical Administrators, 1974-1987 (Box 23, Folder 363)
  - Somers, Anne and Herman, 1969-1987 (Box 23, Folder 364)
  - Southern Illinois University, 1971-1972 (Box 23, Folder 365)
  - Sparks family, 1980-1987 (Box 23, Folder 366)
  - Spence, Moriarity and Schuster, 1984-1985 (Box 23, Folder 367)
  - Stagl, John M., 1974-1976 (Box 23, Folder 368)
  - Stanford Medical Alumni Association, 1975-1987 (Box 23, Folder 369)
  - Stanford Medical Fund, 1981-1987 (Box 23, Folder 370)
  - Stanford University, 1956-1986 (Box 23, Folder 371)
  - Stanford University Medical Center
    See: folders 5, 34, 37, 95, 109, 111, 337-339, 414
  - Stelling, Henry and Elizabeth, 1982-1987 (Box 23, Folder 372)
  - Sterner, Eleanor, 1976-1977 (Box 23, Folder 373)
  - Stevenson, George A., 1951-1952 (Box 23, Folder 374)
  - Stokes, Catherine, 1973-1987 (Box 23, Folder 375)
    See also: folder 40
  - Storey, Margaret Hamilton, 1942-1951 (Box 23, Folder 376)
  - Storey, Thomas A. and Parnie, 1934-1943 (Box 23, Folder 377)
  - Strathairn, Pamela, 1979-1986 (Box 23, Folder 378)
  - Stronach, William C., 1955-1963 (Box 23, Folder 379)
  - Stuhl, Vera, 1969-1975 (Box 23, Folder 380)
  - T (Box 23, Folder 381)
  - Taylor, Cynthia, 1983-1987 (Box 23, Folder 382)
  - Terenzio, Joseph, 1954-1980 (Box 23, Folder 383)
  - Thalken, Thomas, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 384)
  - Thompson, John, 1959-1986 (Box 24, Folder 385)
  - Tilson, John Q., Jr., 1955-1987 (Box 24, Folder 386)
  - Tripp, Edward, 1974-1988 (Box 24, Folder 387)
  - Trotman, Stanley S., 1958-1986 (Box 24, Folder 388)
  - Trussell, Ray E., 1965 (Box 24, Folder 389)
    See also: folder 7
  - Turner, J. Gilbert, 1965-1966 (Box 24, Folder 390)
  - U (Box 24, Folder 391)
  - United States
    - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1966-1976 (Box 24, Folder 392)
    - Public Health Service, 1942-1943 (Box 24, Folder 393)
  - United Way of Greater New Haven, 1978-1987 (Box 24, Folder 394)
  - University of Delaware, 1968-1969 (Box 24, Folder 395)
  - University of Illinois, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 396)
  - University of Kentucky, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 397)
  - University of Louisville Health Sciences Center, 1973-1975 (Box 24, Folder 398)
  - University of Toledo Law Review, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 399)
  - V (Box 25, Folder 400)
  - Van Syckle, Guy W., 1976-1978 (Box 25, Folder 401)
  - Wa-We (Box 25, Folder 402)
  - Wh-Wy (Box 25, Folder 403)
  - Washington (state), 1971-1975 (Box 25, Folder 404)
  - Washington State Historical Society, 1979-1984 (Box 25, Folder 405)
  - Webb, Samuel, 1981-1982 (Box 25, Folder 406)
  - Webb, William
    See: folder 204
  - Wedmore, Barbara and Richard, 1978-1987 (Box 25, Folder 407)
  - Weeks, Lewis [re: oral history], 1986-1988 (Box 25, Folder 408)
  - Welch, Harold, 1956-1985 (Box 25, Folder 409)
  - Wells, Ruth, 1966-1987 (Box 25, Folder 410)
  - Wenkert, Walter, 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 411)
  - Westbury, Stuart A., 1982-1987 (Box 25, Folder 412)
  - Whalen, Brian, 1968-1973 (Box 25, Folder 413)
  - Wheeler, E. Todd, 1956-1987 (Box 25, Folder 414)
  - White, Thomas, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 415)
  - Wiggin, Frederick H., 1945-1961 (Box 26, Folder 416)
  - Williams, Kenneth J., 1963-1972 (Box 26, Folder 417)
  - Williamson, Kenneth, 1963-1972 (Box 26, Folder 418)
  - Wilson, David and Elizabeth, 1972-1988 (Box 26, Folder 419)
  - Wilson, William, 1954-1988 (Box 26, Folder 420)
  - Winthrop, Stimson, Putnam, and Roberts [attorneys for Bristol-Myers], 1968 (Box 26, Folder 421)
  - Wisconsin (state), 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 422)
  - Womer, Charles, 1966-1976 (Box 26, Folder 423)
  - Worcester City Hospital, 1956-1962 (Box 26, Folder 424)
  - Wright, Gardner F., 1983-1988 (Box 26, Folder 425)
  - Y (Box 26, Folder 426)
  - Yale-New Haven Hospital, 1965-1984 (Box 26, Folder 427)
  - Yale-New Haven Hospital Auxiliary, 1968-1987 (Box 26, Folder 428)
  - Yale University, 1946-1988 (Box 26, Folder 429)
    See also: folder 322
  - Yale University Press, 1985-1988 (Box 26, Folder 430)
  - Yoder, Franklin D., 1970 (Box 27, Folder 431)
  - Yokogawa, Kachiko, 1982-1986 (Box 27, Folder 432)
  - Yoshida, Yukio, 1964-1988 (Box 27, Folder 433)
  - Z (Box 27, Folder 434)
  - Ziebell, Harold O., 1972 (Box 27, Folder 435)
  - Unidentified (Box 27, Folder 436)
- WRITINGS, 1937-1988; Series II
  Series II is composed of drafts and printed copies of Albert Snoke's writings, which take the form of books, articles, reviews, speeches, and reports. As a consultant to numerous hospitals and medical centers, Snoke was called upon to supply written reports. These are arranged at the beginning of the series under the heading "Consultations." The files here are arranged in chronological order and for an individual consultation the file may include background material and notes as well as drafts and the completed report. A large number of reports concern medical institutions in Connecticut and Illinois. There is also a major report to the Health Sciences Education Committee of the Council on Public Higher Education of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.
  Files for writings listed by Snoke in his bibliography, a copy of which may be found in box 48, folder 5, are arranged after the consultations under the heading "Bibliographic items." These files are arranged in numerical order according to Snoke's numbering system. Not all bibliographic items, however, are represented in the papers. The files are basically in chronological order. Snoke has included in his bibliography articles and addresses, as well as some formal reports and memoranda, such as those prepared for the Select Advisory Panel on Human Service Organization of the Connecticut Association for Human Services or for the governor of Illinois.
  Files for speeches and writings not included in Snoke's bibliography are arranged under the heading "Non-bibliographic items" in chronological order. The documentation for many of these items is briefer or less formal than those in the bibliography. The files may only contain an outline or notes for a talk or a brief typescript for a book review. Since, however, Snoke's bibliography includes only two titles published after 1975, files for some "non-bibliographic" items are similar to those included on the bibliography. There are extensive materials for Snoke's attempts to write a book on implementing a national health care program in the late 1970s and early 1980s and other materials for his 1987 volume, Hospitals, Health, and People. There are also files for a 1980 history of the Medical Administrators Conference, an oral history for the American Hospital Association, and the outlines and drafts for a second book.
  - Consultations
    - The Society of the New York Hospital and Cornell University Medical College, 1942 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Dearborn Hospital Commission, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Report of Survey--Hospitals of Utica, New York, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - University of Illinois--Research and Educational Hospitals; Additions and Improvements, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Greater Boston Community Survey, Hospital Division
      - Second draft, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Final draft, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Published report, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Reports of the Hospital Council relative to the Survey, Hospital Division, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - A Survey of the Worcester City Hospital and the Belmont Hospital of Worcester, Massachusetts, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - A Survey of the Southern New London County Community Hospital Facilities, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - A Survey of the Windham Community Memorial Hospital, Inc., Willimantic, Connecticut, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Report to the County Council, County of Charleston, South Carolina, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - A Program for Planning a Medical Center for the American University of Beirut, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - A Survey of the William W. Backus Hospital, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - A Survey of the Lawrence and Memorial Hospitals, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 15)
      See also: Series I, folders 10, 190, 219, 241, 321 (Ryle)
    - A Report on the Pacific Medical Center, 1968
      - Report, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - Background material, 1961-1968 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - A Report on the Major Hospitals of the Province of Saskatchewan; Presented to the Minister of Health
      - Final copy, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 18)
      - Background material and notes, ca., 1957-1968 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - A Report on the Cook County Health Care Institutions
      See also: Series I, folders 162, 196, 289-293, 341 (Sibley), 413
      - Final copy, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 20-21)
      - Background material, 1939, 1964-1968 (Box 30, Folder 22-27)
      - Background material, 1964-1968 (Box 31, Folder 28-30)
      - Drafts, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 31)
      - Notes, 1968 Jun-Aug, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 32-35)
    - A Report to the Joint Study Committee of the Northwest Region of Connecticut
      - Final copy, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 36)
        General
        See also: Series I, folders 29 (Beloff and Bergeron), 91, 125 (Elling), 137, 142, 149 (Green, Lee), 190, 200 (Kellogg), 215 (Lewis, George), 216 (Litchfield), 287, 300 (Patterson), 343 (Sternlof)
      - Background material and notes
        - General, 1967-1969 (Box 31, Folder 37)
        - Charlotte Hungerford Hospital, 1967-1969 (Box 31, Folder 38)
        - Sharon Hospital, 1967-1969 (Box 31, Folder 39)
        - Winsted Memorial Hospital, 1968-1969 (Box 31, Folder 40)
    - A Report to the Health Sciences Education Committee of the Council on Public Higher Education of the Commonwealth of Kentucky on Health Sciences Education and Manpower in the Commonwealth of Kentucky
      - Final copy, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 41)
        See also: Series I, folders 40, 127, 132, 204, 375, 397, 398
      - Background material
        - General, 1970-1973 (Box 32, Folder 42)
        - Eastern Kentucky University, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 43)
        - Falls Region, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 44)
        - Louisville General Hospital, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 45)
        - University of Kentucky, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 46)
        - University of Louisville, 1973-1975 (Box 32, Folder 47)
      - Notes, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 48)
    - University of Illinois Hospital
      - Final copy, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 49)
        See also: Series I, folders 236, 346, 396
      - Background material
        - 1980-1981 (Box 32, Folder 50-51)
        - 1983-1986 (Box 33, Folder 52-56)
  - Bibliographic items
    - 1. Stages, Prognosis and Duration of Glomerular Nephritis in Childhood, 1937 (Box 34, Folder 57)
    - 2. The Normal Addis Sediment Count in Children, 1938 (Box 34, Folder 58)
    - 3. Prognosis of Glomerular Nephritis in Childhood, 1939 (Box 34, Folder 59)
    - 4. Decentralized Refrigeration and Ice Making in Hospitals, 1940 (Box 34, Folder 60)
    - 5. Ether Economy or Waste?, 1940-1941 (Box 34, Folder 61)
    - 6. You Ought to Autoclave, 1942 (Box 34, Folder 62)
    - 8. Standard Insurance Report Forms, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 63)
    - 9. Modern Utility Room, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 64)
    - 9a. Who is Regimenting Now?, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 65)
    - 10. Hospital Service and X-Ray, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 66)
    - 11. Flat Rate, All Inclusive Plan May Be the Answer in Welfare Out-Patient Care, 1945 (Box 34, Folder 67)
    - 12. Three Procedures that Help Curb Airborne Infection, 1945 (Box 34, Folder 68)
    - 13. Rates--Quoted at Cost and Adjusted to Patient's Financial Condition, 1947 (Box 34, Folder 69)
    - 14. A Hospital Rooming-in Unit for Newborns and Mothers, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 70)
    - 17. Three Viewpoints on Hospital Costs, 1951 (Box 34, Folder 71)
    - 18. Cooperation between Medical and Administrative Staffs (to reduce hospital costs), 1952 (Box 34, Folder 72)
    - 19. A Step Forward in Hospital-Physician Relationships, 1953 (Box 34, Folder 73)
    - 20. The Shortage of Nurses, 1953 (Box 34, Folder 74)
    - 21. The Role of the Hospital in the Medical Care of Tomorrow's Patient, 1953-1954 (Box 34, Folder 75)
    - 22. Hospital-Physician Relationships, 1954 (Box 34, Folder 76)